<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IaC on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/categories/iac/</link><description>Recent content in IaC on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/categories/iac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🖥️ Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure•Part 2</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="../../03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/">Part 1&lt;/a>, we set up our development environment and deployed our first Azure resource group using Terraform. Whilst this gave us a taste of Infrastructure as Code, we were using local state files: a practice that won&amp;rsquo;t scale for team environments or production workloads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this second part of our series, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore &lt;strong>Terraform state management&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>remote backends&lt;/strong>. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn why state is crucial, how to configure Azure Storage as a remote backend, implement state locking for team safety, and master essential state management commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>⚖️ Azure Bicep vs Terraform: What Should You Choose?</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/azure-bicep-vs-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/azure-bicep-vs-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Infrastructure as Code (IaC) is a critical part of modern cloud development, allowing teams to define and manage infrastructure in a declarative and repeatable way. Two of the most popular IaC tools for Microsoft Azure are &lt;strong>Azure Bicep&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Terraform&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But which one should you use? This article compares Bicep and Terraform based on syntax, features, ease of use, ecosystem support, and real-world scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-azure-bicep">&lt;strong>What is Azure Bicep?&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Azure Bicep is a &lt;strong>domain-specific language (DSL)&lt;/strong> developed by Microsoft as an abstraction over ARM (Azure Resource Manager) templates. It simplifies Azure infrastructure deployment by providing a cleaner syntax compared to JSON-based ARM templates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🖥️ Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure•Part 1</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Terraform is a powerful Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool that enables you to define, provision, and manage Azure resources using declarative configuration files. This blog series, &lt;em>Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure&lt;/em>, will take you through Terraform from the basics to advanced topics, using hands-on examples tailored for Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this first post, we’ll focus on setting up your development environment and deploying your first resource on Azure using Terraform.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>