<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>V1.35 on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/v1.35/</link><description>Recent content in V1.35 on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/v1.35/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Restricting executables invoked by kubeconfigs via exec plugin allowList added to kuberc</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-restricting-executables-invoked-by-kubeconfigs-via-exec-plugin-allowlist-added-to-kuberc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-restricting-executables-invoked-by-kubeconfigs-via-exec-plugin-allowlist-added-to-kuberc/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces a beta credential plugin policy and allowlist to give users control over executables invoked by kubeconfig exec plugins. You can set policy via the client-go ExecProvider.PluginPolicy or by configuring kubectl&amp;rsquo;s kuberc with credentialPluginPolicy (AllowAll, DenyAll, Allowlist) and credentialPluginAllowlist entries to restrict which plugins may run.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2026/01/09/kubernetes-v1-35-kuberc-credential-plugin-allowlist/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Mutable PersistentVolume Node Affinity (alpha)</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-mutable-persistentvolume-node-affinity-alpha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-mutable-persistentvolume-node-affinity-alpha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 (alpha) makes PersistentVolume.spec.nodeAffinity mutable. This allows administrators to update PV node affinity to match changes in underlying storage (for example zonal→regional migrations or disk-generation upgrades) without recreating the PV. The feature is gated (MutablePVNodeAffinity), disabled by default, and requires updating the storage provider first. Be aware of scheduling race conditions when tightening affinity; future kubelet/CSI integration and VolumeAttributesClass automation are planned. Feedback is requested via SIG Storage channels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: A Better Way to Pass Service Account Tokens to CSI Drivers</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-a-better-way-to-pass-service-account-tokens-to-csi-drivers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-a-better-way-to-pass-service-account-tokens-to-csi-drivers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces a beta opt-in for delivering CSI-requested service account tokens in the NodePublishVolumeRequest secrets field rather than volume_context. This change (controlled by serviceAccountTokenInSecrets in the CSIDriver spec) fixes accidental token exposure in logs, is opt-in to preserve compatibility, and includes guidance and a safe rollout sequence for CSI driver authors.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2026/01/07/kubernetes-v1-35-csi-sa-tokens-secrets-field-beta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Extended Toleration Operators to Support Numeric Comparisons (Alpha)</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-extended-toleration-operators-to-support-numeric-comparisons-alpha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-extended-toleration-operators-to-support-numeric-comparisons-alpha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces Extended Toleration Operators (alpha) that add numeric comparison operators Gt and Lt to spec.tolerations. This lets tolerations compare numeric taint values (e.g., failure-probability, gpu-compute-score, disk-iops, cost-per-hour) so schedulers can make threshold-based placement decisions while preserving taint/toleration semantics (centralized node-side policy and eviction via NoExecute). The feature is gated, supports all taint effects, has specific numeric format rules, and is experimental — feedback and further enhancements (CEL, autoscaling integration, graduation) are planned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: New level of efficiency with in-place Pod restart</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-new-level-of-efficiency-with-in-place-pod-restart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-new-level-of-efficiency-with-in-place-pod-restart/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces an alpha feature, Restart All Containers (enabled with the RestartAllContainersOnContainerExits feature gate), which adds a RestartAllContainers action to container restart rules to perform a fast, in-place full Pod restart that preserves Pod UID, IP, sandbox and volumes while re-running init, sidecar and application containers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2026/01/02/kubernetes-v1-35-restart-all-containers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes 1.35: Enhanced Debugging with Versioned z-pages APIs</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-enhanced-debugging-with-versioned-z-pages-apis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-enhanced-debugging-with-versioned-z-pages-apis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes 1.35 adds opt-in, versioned, machine-parseable JSON responses for the existing /statusz and /flagz z-pages used by control plane components. The endpoints remain backward compatible (plain text by default); consumers request structured output by sending an Accept header with a versioned media type. Structured responses enable easier automation for health checks, config validation, and debugging tools. The feature is alpha, requires feature gates and proper RBAC/authentication, and is intended for debugging rather than production-critical automation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Watch Based Route Reconciliation in the Cloud Controller Manager</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-watch-based-route-reconciliation-in-the-cloud-controller-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-watch-based-route-reconciliation-in-the-cloud-controller-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces an alpha feature gate (CloudControllerManagerWatchBasedRoutesReconciliation) in k8s.io/cloud-provider that changes the CCM route controller from a fixed-interval reconciliation to a watch/informer-based trigger model. The change reduces unnecessary cloud API calls by reconciling routes only when relevant node or CIDR/address fields change, with an additional randomized periodic reconcile every 12–24 hours. The reconciliation logic itself is unchanged and the feature is enabled via &amp;ndash;feature-gate.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/30/kubernetes-v1-35-watch-based-route-reconciliation-in-ccm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Introducing Workload Aware Scheduling</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-introducing-workload-aware-scheduling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-introducing-workload-aware-scheduling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces workload-aware scheduling with a new Workload API (scheduling.k8s.io/v1alpha1) to describe multi-Pod scheduling requirements, an initial gang scheduling implementation for all-or-nothing placement, and opportunistic batching (Beta) to speed scheduling of identical Pods. Gang scheduling uses podGroups, a workloadRef on Pods, and a Permit gate with a 5-minute timeout; opportunistic batching reuses feasibility checks for identical Pods but has strict identical-field restrictions. The release also outlines a broader roadmap (workload-level preemption, autoscaling integration, topology-aware scheduling) and explains required feature gates and how to test and give feedback.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Fine-grained Supplemental Groups Control Graduates to GA</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-fine-grained-supplemental-groups-control-graduates-to-ga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-fine-grained-supplemental-groups-control-graduates-to-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 graduates fine-grained supplemental groups control to GA via a new Pod field, supplementalGroupsPolicy, letting clusters choose whether to merge group memberships from the container image (/etc/group) or enforce only groups declared in the Pod (Strict) to reduce implicit, hard-to-audit GIDs and improve security (especially for volume access).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/23/kubernetes-v1-35-fine-grained-supplementalgroups-control-ga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Kubelet Configuration Drop-in Directory Graduates to GA</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-configuration-drop-in-directory-graduates-to-ga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-configuration-drop-in-directory-graduates-to-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 graduates the kubelet configuration drop-in directory to GA: the &amp;ndash;config-dir kubelet flag is now production-ready and automatically merges drop-in files with the main kubelet configuration. This simplifies managing different kubelet settings across heterogeneous node pools and supports staged rollouts and targeted overrides without complex tooling.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/22/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-config-drop-in-directory-ga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes 1.35: In-Place Pod Resize Graduates to Stable</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-in-place-pod-resize-graduates-to-stable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-in-place-pod-resize-graduates-to-stable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes 1.35 graduates In-Place Pod Resize (In-Place Pod Vertical Scaling) to stable (GA). The feature makes CPU and memory requests and limits mutable on a running Pod (via a resize subresource), often without restarting containers. This enables non-disruptive resource adjustments, more powerful autoscaling (e.g., VPA InPlaceOrRecreate), transient boosts like CPU startup boost, and better resource efficiency. The release also adds prioritized retries, allows memory limit decreases (best-effort OOM protection), alpha support for Pod Level Resources, and new kubelet metrics/events. Work remains on runtime support, scheduler/kubelet races, expanded feature support, and integrations with autoscalers and other projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Job Managed By Goes GA</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-job-managed-by-goes-ga/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-job-managed-by-goes-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 promotes .spec.managedBy for Jobs to GA, enabling external controllers (e.g., MultiKueue) to take full responsibility for Job reconciliation and enabling multi-cluster batch scheduling patterns while leaving built-in Job controller behavior intact for other Jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/18/kubernetes-v1-35-job-managedby-for-jobs-goes-ga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Timbernetes (The World Tree Release)</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-timbernetes-the-world-tree-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-timbernetes-the-world-tree-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 (&amp;ldquo;Timbernetes / World Tree&amp;rdquo; release) ships 60 enhancements (17 stable, 19 beta, 22 alpha), focused on smoother nondisruptive scaling, native pod certificate-based workload identity, improved scheduling correctness, storage and topology improvements, and several important deprecations/removals. The release emphasizes stability, performance, and security hardening (notable GA features, new betas/alphas, and migration guidance for cgroup and containerd).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/17/kubernetes-v1-35-release/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35 Sneak Peek</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-sneak-peek/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-sneak-peek/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 (planned 2025-12-17) introduces several deprecations and new/advanced features. Major removals/deprecations include cgroup v1 support removal, deprecation of kube-proxy ipvs mode, and final support for containerd v1.x (users must move to containerd 2.0+). Notable enhancements likely in v1.35 include node declared features (alpha), in-place Pod resource updates (GA), pod certificates (beta), numeric taint comparisons, continued progress on user namespaces, and image volumes becoming default.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/11/26/kubernetes-v1-35-sneak-peek/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>