<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VS Code on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/tags/vs-code/</link><description>Recent content in VS Code on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/tags/vs-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🛠️ GitHub Copilot: Custom Instructions, Prompts &amp; Chats</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/07/customize-github-copilot-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/07/customize-github-copilot-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-customizing-your-github-copilot-experience-instructions-prompts-and-chat-modes">🛠️ Customizing Your GitHub Copilot Experience: Instructions, Prompts, and Chat Modes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GitHub Copilot is more than just an autocomplete tool—it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful AI assistant you can tailor to your team&amp;rsquo;s needs. With the latest features in VS Code, you can now define custom instructions, prompts, and chat modes to make Copilot work exactly the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post walks you through customizing Copilot for your projects, with hands-on steps, theory, and examples. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🤖 GitHub Copilot Agent: Your AI Pair Programmer</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/04/github-copilot-agent-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/04/github-copilot-agent-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>GitHub Copilot just levelled up. The long-anticipated &lt;strong>Agent Mode&lt;/strong> is no longer in preview and is officially rolling out to all users of &lt;strong>Visual Studio Code&lt;/strong>, including the stable release. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever dreamed of having a truly &lt;strong>autonomous AI pair programmer&lt;/strong> that doesn&amp;rsquo;t just suggest lines of code but actively edits files, runs commands, and debugs your code — your wish has come true.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-is-copilot-agent-mode">💡 What is Copilot Agent Mode?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Agent Mode is a major upgrade to GitHub Copilot. Unlike traditional autocomplete and inline suggestions, &lt;strong>Agent Mode enables Copilot to understand your workspace and perform complex, multi-step tasks&lt;/strong> — from generating code to fixing bugs, running tests, editing multiple files, and executing terminal commands.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>