<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubelet on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/kubelet/</link><description>Recent content in Kubelet on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/kubelet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Kubelet Configuration Drop-in Directory Graduates to GA</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-configuration-drop-in-directory-graduates-to-ga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-configuration-drop-in-directory-graduates-to-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 graduates the kubelet configuration drop-in directory to GA: the &amp;ndash;config-dir kubelet flag is now production-ready and automatically merges drop-in files with the main kubelet configuration. This simplifies managing different kubelet settings across heterogeneous node pools and supports staged rollouts and targeted overrides without complex tooling.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/12/22/kubernetes-v1-35-kubelet-config-drop-in-directory-ga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes 1.35: In-Place Pod Resize Graduates to Stable</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-in-place-pod-resize-graduates-to-stable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-1-35-in-place-pod-resize-graduates-to-stable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes 1.35 graduates In-Place Pod Resize (In-Place Pod Vertical Scaling) to stable (GA). The feature makes CPU and memory requests and limits mutable on a running Pod (via a resize subresource), often without restarting containers. This enables non-disruptive resource adjustments, more powerful autoscaling (e.g., VPA InPlaceOrRecreate), transient boosts like CPU startup boost, and better resource efficiency. The release also adds prioritized retries, allows memory limit decreases (best-effort OOM protection), alpha support for Pod Level Resources, and new kubelet metrics/events. Work remains on runtime support, scheduler/kubelet races, expanded feature support, and integrations with autoscalers and other projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.34: Pods Report DRA Resource Health</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-34-pods-report-dra-resource-health/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-34-pods-report-dra-resource-health/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.34 introduces an alpha feature (ResourceHealthStatus) that lets Dynamic Resource Allocation (DRA) drivers report device health into a Pod&amp;rsquo;s status via a new dra-health/v1alpha1 gRPC service, enabling the Kubelet to surface per-device health in v1.ContainerStatus. This improves debuggability for hardware-backed workloads by showing device health (Healthy/Unhealthy/Unknown) in allocatedResourcesStatus and requires enabling the feature gate and compatible DRA drivers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/09/17/kubernetes-v1-34-pods-report-dra-resource-health/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>