<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machine Learning on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🤖 GitHub Copilot Certification Guide (GH-300) - AI Development Mastery</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/github-certification-journey-gh-300/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/github-certification-journey-gh-300/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to Part 4 of the &lt;strong>GitHub Certification Journey&lt;/strong>! 🤖&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After mastering GitHub Foundations (GH-900), GitHub Administration (GH-100), and GitHub Actions (GH-200), you&amp;rsquo;re ready to embrace the future of software development with &lt;strong>GitHub Copilot&lt;/strong> - the revolutionary AI pair programmer that transforms how developers write, review, and maintain code. The &lt;strong>GH-300 GitHub Copilot&lt;/strong> certification validates your expertise in AI-powered development workflows, prompt engineering, and enterprise AI governance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This comprehensive guide provides everything needed to pass the GH-300 exam and become a GitHub Copilot expert. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer seeking to amplify productivity, a team lead implementing AI development practices, or an enterprise architect designing AI-powered development strategies, this preparation roadmap will take you from basic AI assistance to advanced enterprise Copilot mastery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🚀 GitHub Copilot: The AI-Powered Coding Assistant</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/github-copilot-the-ai-powered-coding-assistant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/github-copilot-the-ai-powered-coding-assistant/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GitHub Copilot is an AI-powered coding assistant developed by GitHub in collaboration with OpenAI. It acts as a pair programmer, providing real-time code suggestions, autocompletions, and entire function implementations based on context. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re writing JavaScript, Python, C#, or even Terraform, Copilot speeds up development and improves productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, we’ll explore what GitHub Copilot is, how it works, its benefits, limitations, and best practices for maximizing its potential.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>