<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/categories/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🤖 When to Use GitHub Models, Azure AI Foundry, and OpenAI</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/09/when-to-use-github-models-azure-ai-foundry-openai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/09/when-to-use-github-models-azure-ai-foundry-openai/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-when-to-use-github-models-azure-ai-foundry-and-openai">🤖 When to Use GitHub Models, Azure AI Foundry, and OpenAI&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Artificial intelligence is moving fast, and so are the platforms that deliver it.&lt;br>
For many teams, the question isn’t &lt;em>“Can we use AI?”&lt;/em> but &lt;em>“Where should we use it from?”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Between &lt;strong>GitHub Models&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Azure AI Foundry&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>OpenAI&lt;/strong>, developers and enterprises alike face an abundance of choice. The reality is that there is no single “best” option — the right one depends on your perspective and your stage in the AI journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🖥️ Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure•Part 2</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="../../03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/">Part 1&lt;/a>, we set up our development environment and deployed our first Azure resource group using Terraform. Whilst this gave us a taste of Infrastructure as Code, we were using local state files: a practice that won&amp;rsquo;t scale for team environments or production workloads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this second part of our series, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore &lt;strong>Terraform state management&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>remote backends&lt;/strong>. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn why state is crucial, how to configure Azure Storage as a remote backend, implement state locking for team safety, and master essential state management commands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🖥️ Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure•Part 1</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/03/zero-to-hero-terraform-for-azure-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Terraform is a powerful Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool that enables you to define, provision, and manage Azure resources using declarative configuration files. This blog series, &lt;em>Zero to Hero: Terraform for Azure&lt;/em>, will take you through Terraform from the basics to advanced topics, using hands-on examples tailored for Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this first post, we’ll focus on setting up your development environment and deploying your first resource on Azure using Terraform.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>