<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scheduling on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/scheduling/</link><description>Recent content in Scheduling on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/update_tags/scheduling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>k8s: Announcing the Checkpoint/Restore Working Group</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/announcing-the-checkpoint-restore-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/announcing-the-checkpoint-restore-working-group/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes has launched the Checkpoint Restore Working Group to advance integration of checkpoint/restore functionality (primarily via the CRIU ecosystem) into Kubernetes. The WG will explore use cases like faster startup, resource optimization for interactive AI workloads, fault-tolerance for long runs, interruption-aware scheduling, live Pod migration, and forensic checkpointing, and invites contributors to join meetings, Slack, and the mailing list.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2026/01/21/introducing-checkpoint-restore-wg/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Extended Toleration Operators to Support Numeric Comparisons (Alpha)</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-extended-toleration-operators-to-support-numeric-comparisons-alpha/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-extended-toleration-operators-to-support-numeric-comparisons-alpha/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces Extended Toleration Operators (alpha) that add numeric comparison operators Gt and Lt to spec.tolerations. This lets tolerations compare numeric taint values (e.g., failure-probability, gpu-compute-score, disk-iops, cost-per-hour) so schedulers can make threshold-based placement decisions while preserving taint/toleration semantics (centralized node-side policy and eviction via NoExecute). The feature is gated, supports all taint effects, has specific numeric format rules, and is experimental — feedback and further enhancements (CEL, autoscaling integration, graduation) are planned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.35: Introducing Workload Aware Scheduling</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-introducing-workload-aware-scheduling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-35-introducing-workload-aware-scheduling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.35 introduces workload-aware scheduling with a new Workload API (scheduling.k8s.io/v1alpha1) to describe multi-Pod scheduling requirements, an initial gang scheduling implementation for all-or-nothing placement, and opportunistic batching (Beta) to speed scheduling of identical Pods. Gang scheduling uses podGroups, a workloadRef on Pods, and a Permit gate with a 5-minute timeout; opportunistic batching reuses feasibility checks for identical Pods but has strict identical-field restrictions. The release also outlines a broader roadmap (workload-level preemption, autoscaling integration, topology-aware scheduling) and explains required feature gates and how to test and give feedback.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>k8s: Kubernetes v1.34: Pod Level Resources Graduated to Beta</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-34-pod-level-resources-graduated-to-beta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/updates/kubernetes-v1-34-pod-level-resources-graduated-to-beta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes v1.34 graduates Pod Level Resources to Beta and enables it by default. The feature lets you declare CPU, memory and hugepages for an entire Pod (in addition to per-container settings), with pod-level requests used for scheduling and pod-level limits acting as an absolute runtime cap; it improves intra-pod sharing and QoS handling but has several platform and feature limitations.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Source:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2025/09/22/kubernetes-v1-34-pod-level-resources/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Official Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>