<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Sujith Quintelier</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Sujith Quintelier</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quintelier.dev/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🤖 GitHub Copilot Certification Guide (GH-300) - AI Development Mastery</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/github-certification-journey-gh-300/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/08/github-certification-journey-gh-300/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Welcome to Part 4 of the &lt;strong>GitHub Certification Journey&lt;/strong>! 🤖&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After mastering GitHub Foundations (GH-900), GitHub Administration (GH-100), and GitHub Actions (GH-200), you&amp;rsquo;re ready to embrace the future of software development with &lt;strong>GitHub Copilot&lt;/strong> - the revolutionary AI pair programmer that transforms how developers write, review, and maintain code. The &lt;strong>GH-300 GitHub Copilot&lt;/strong> certification validates your expertise in AI-powered development workflows, prompt engineering, and enterprise AI governance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This comprehensive guide provides everything needed to pass the GH-300 exam and become a GitHub Copilot expert. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer seeking to amplify productivity, a team lead implementing AI development practices, or an enterprise architect designing AI-powered development strategies, this preparation roadmap will take you from basic AI assistance to advanced enterprise Copilot mastery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🛠️ GitHub Copilot: Custom Instructions, Prompts &amp; Chats</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/07/customize-github-copilot-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/07/customize-github-copilot-experience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-customizing-your-github-copilot-experience-instructions-prompts-and-chat-modes">🛠️ Customizing Your GitHub Copilot Experience: Instructions, Prompts, and Chat Modes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GitHub Copilot is more than just an autocomplete tool—it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful AI assistant you can tailor to your team&amp;rsquo;s needs. With the latest features in VS Code, you can now define custom instructions, prompts, and chat modes to make Copilot work exactly the way you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post walks you through customizing Copilot for your projects, with hands-on steps, theory, and examples. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🚀 Find Stale Branches Across All GitHub Repos</title><link>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/01/retrieve-stale-branches-github-organization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://quintelier.dev/posts/2025/01/retrieve-stale-branches-github-organization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Keeping your GitHub repositories clean is crucial for maintainability. Over time, branches pile up, making it difficult to track what’s relevant. If you’re managing multiple repositories in an organization, manually identifying stale branches can be a hassle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, with the &lt;strong>GitHub CLI (&lt;code>gh&lt;/code>)&lt;/strong>, you can automate this process and generate a &lt;strong>report of all non-main branches along with their last authors&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide walks you through a &lt;strong>Bash script&lt;/strong> that:&lt;br>
✅ Retrieves all repositories in an organization&lt;br>
✅ Lists branches, excluding &lt;code>main&lt;/code>, &lt;code>master&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>azure-master&lt;/code>&lt;br>
✅ Identifies the last commit author for each branch&lt;br>
✅ Groups the results by author for better visibility&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>